<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Locally Optimal - misc</title><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.locallyoptimal.com/</id><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><subtitle>hill climbing in SF</subtitle><entry><title>Foster informal connections</title><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2020/06/30/foster-informal-connections/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Scott Triglia</name></author><id>tag:www.locallyoptimal.com,2020-06-30:/blog/2020/06/30/foster-informal-connections/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always found fostering informal relationships surprisingly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is such a limited resource, and it's easy to convince yourself to take a mercenary approach to any scheduling. If you aren't getting predictable value out of it, and it's not required by your job, it's not worth your time! But …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've always found fostering informal relationships surprisingly valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is such a limited resource, and it's easy to convince yourself to take a mercenary approach to any scheduling. If you aren't getting predictable value out of it, and it's not required by your job, it's not worth your time! But especially in a Coronavirus world, filled with indefinite remote work and friends trapped behind tiny Zoom panes, this feels like a lonely trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, human nature is important. The difference in outcomes between asking a favor of a colleague you talk with regularly, vs someone you've spoken to only once, vs someone you have never met is substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the recommendation: make it easy for others to meet you and discuss absolutely whatever is on their mind. Time box this, so it can't overwhelm your other priorities. You can do this via word of mouth, but I like going further and explicitly blocking time on my calendar. Set up a finite set of 30 minute slots every week, and subtly advertise them as bookable. No permission needed to book a slot, they're there if anyone wants to talk to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part -- if nobody books a given slot, I get the time back. Zero cost in the early days when nobody knows the slots exist, or I'm not interesting enough for a random coffee chat to feel worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this for most of 2019 while I worked at Yelp, and it was a wonderful way to meet new people, hear about efforts or ideas I'd never otherwise been exposed to, and generally broaden my own connections &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; I needed to rely on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also do this with things that aren't synchronous meetings. Arguably that's even smarter and more time-efficient on your part. See &lt;a href="https://www.kalzumeus.com/standing-invitation/"&gt;patio11's Standing Invitation&lt;/a&gt; to email  as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only risk here is my ego being bruised after the Nth week of no interest. But like many things, this always start out slow, and grows over time. And while it's not easy to follow, I aspire to the advice to "if you aren't being regularly rejected, you aren't putting yourself out there enough".&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>Publish independently and publish often</title><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2019/03/24/publish-independently-publish-often/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Scott Triglia</name></author><id>tag:www.locallyoptimal.com,2019-03-24:/blog/2019/03/24/publish-independently-publish-often/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got sideswiped this a confluence of factors that finally convinced me to resurrect a decent static site generator (hi Pelican!) and bring this blog back from the relative dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast succession: Medium finally locked &lt;a href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018834314-Stories-that-are-part-of-the-metered-paywall"&gt;all useful distribution they do behind an even stronger paywall&lt;/a&gt;, I &lt;a href="https://avc.com/2018/01/owning-yourself/"&gt;read this article&lt;/a&gt; by Fred Wilson on the value of being self-sufficient, and the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/patio11"&gt;one and only patio11&lt;/a&gt;  kindly responded to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scott_triglia/status/1106274981355220992"&gt;some of my questions about how to bootstrap a fledgling website&lt;/a&gt; no one visits out of the cold start problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm going to primarily be writing on my own blog (e.g. this post at http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2019/03/24/publish-independently-publish-often/), syndicating posts across to Medium for a least a bit, and seeing how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got sideswiped this a confluence of factors that finally convinced me to resurrect a decent static site generator (hi Pelican!) and bring this blog back from the relative dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast succession: Medium finally locked &lt;a href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/360018834314-Stories-that-are-part-of-the-metered-paywall"&gt;all useful distribution they do behind an even stronger paywall&lt;/a&gt;, I &lt;a href="https://avc.com/2018/01/owning-yourself/"&gt;read this article&lt;/a&gt; by Fred Wilson on the value of being self-sufficient, and the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/patio11"&gt;one and only patio11&lt;/a&gt;  kindly responded to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/scott_triglia/status/1106274981355220992"&gt;some of my questions about how to bootstrap a fledgling website&lt;/a&gt; no one visits out of the cold start problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm going to primarily be writing on my own blog (e.g. this post at http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2019/03/24/publish-independently-publish-often/), syndicating posts across to Medium for a least a bit, and seeing how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;A new site generator&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got fed up with fighting a packaging ecosystem I didn't know well in a language I didn't understand, so I picked this up and took it from Octopress to Pelican. So far there seems to be actively less magic (mostly because I can probably read Makefiles and Python much more natively) and it was easy enough to port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2013/05/07/migrating-from-octopress-to-pelican/"&gt;Credit to an old friend's blog post&lt;/a&gt; showing up unexpectedly in Google results while I tried to work through the port 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Publish independently&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On both Patrick's and Fred's advice, I'm going to try and have this website be the first publishing platform and, where it seems useful, I can syndicate out elsewhere. Seems that &lt;a href="https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/217991468-SEO-and-duplicate-content"&gt;importing content into Medium w/ canonical links isn't too hard&lt;/a&gt;, so I got that going for me. In some ways it seems a shame to lose the &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@scott_triglia"&gt;very small amount of momentum I had on Medium&lt;/a&gt;, but I suppose that makes it cheaper to do now than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still quite nervous that this will be the blogging equivalent of someone divesting themselves of USD and solely transacting with cryptocurrency -- I will definitely be more free of "the man" telling me what to do or who can read my writing, but I may find that I don't like the other dowsides that come with that freedom. Then again, the only way to really know how it goes is to give it a shot in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Publish often&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If history is any indication, this will be the hard part. I've had a pretty good run publishing nearly-weekly posts internal to Yelp in the last 3 months or so, but I've been quite awful at putting them out on the greater internet. That seems like a shame in retrospect, because I've often been frustrated at the extreme rarity of any decent writing on technical leadership for non-managers.  Except this week of course - see &lt;a href="https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/defining-a-distinguished-engineer/"&gt;Jessie Frazelle's excellent post on distinguished engineers&lt;/a&gt; which has immediately become my new favorite post describing the holistic set of skills behind excellent senior engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to better defend my ability to publish often, there's probably going to be a bias here to just text and links for a while. Something I can crank out in a markdown editor without worrying about any technical issues and throw onto the website without effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So here's to nothing?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck -- we'll see if a better generator, some reaffirmed intent, and a coat of new paint do the trick.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>"A New Year"</title><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2013/01/12/a-new-year/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-01-12T15:54:00-08:00</published><updated>2013-01-12T15:54:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Scott Triglia</name></author><id>tag:www.locallyoptimal.com,2013-01-12:/blog/2013/01/12/a-new-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All the cool kids wrote New Year posts, so I figured that was excuse enough for me to chime in with a quick one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing here has been a nice outlet for the end of 2012, but I figure now's as good a time as any to make a couple …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;All the cool kids wrote New Year posts, so I figured that was excuse enough for me to chime in with a quick one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing here has been a nice outlet for the end of 2012, but I figure now's as good a time as any to make a couple minor changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I'm going to actually bother telling people this exists. Theoretically I was waiting until I was more comfortable with the writing, or until I decided this would actually be of interest to other people, or some other unspecified time…but better now than not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I'm planning on publishing a lot more short, one-off posts with little snippets of code I've found useful. Back in grad school I found many a solution in the tiny posts &lt;a href="http://desk.stinkpot.org:8080/tricks/"&gt;from the desk of Stinkpot&lt;/a&gt; and would love to save other people some frustration in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Happy New Year and here's to a great 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>"First things first"</title><link href="http://www.locallyoptimal.com/blog/2012/08/31/first-things-first/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-08-31T23:53:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-08-31T23:53:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Scott Triglia</name></author><id>tag:www.locallyoptimal.com,2012-08-31:/blog/2012/08/31/first-things-first/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As all good internet citizens do eventually, I've decided to try writing down
my various software-related trials and tribulations down in a blog. For the
time being, I'm sticking with Octopress as I care more about the content than
the web design. Maybe later this will become an exercise in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As all good internet citizens do eventually, I've decided to try writing down
my various software-related trials and tribulations down in a blog. For the
time being, I'm sticking with Octopress as I care more about the content than
the web design. Maybe later this will become an exercise in web
development...but not quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect a lot of posts where I walk through some task or tool that I've been
using recently. Hopefully you'll find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category></entry></feed>